Guide to the Time Inc. The March of Time Records 1935-1995 MS 3009-RG 15
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Audiovisual [RESTRICTED], 1979-1995, undated; 12.5 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
  - Subseries IV.A. Internal Use, 1979-1995, undated; 11 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 8 and 10, undated (Offsite-box 2806, Item 15)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #13 Episode #8 and 10"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 8 and 10, undated (Offsite-box 2806, Item 16)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 13 Episode #8 and 10"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 9 and 12 and Vol. 15 Issue 6, undated (Offsite-box 2806, Item 17)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #13 Episodes #9 and 12 Volume #15 Episode #6"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 9 and 12 and Vol. 15 Issue 6, undated (Offsite-box 2806, Item 18)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 13 Episode #9 and 12 Vol 15 Episode #6". On side case label: "91. March of TIME Vol. 13 and 15"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 9 and 12 and Vol. 15 Issues 6, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 1)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #13 Episode #9 and 12 Volume #15 Episode #6"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issue 9 and 12 and Vol. 15 Issue 6, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 2)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 13 Episode #9 and 12 Vol 15 Episode #6"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 11 and 13, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 3)
      1 videocasssette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 13 Episode #11 and 13". On side case label: "92. March of TIME Vol. 13, Ep. #11 and 13"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 11 and 13, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 4)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #13 Episode #11 and 13"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 11 and 13, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 5)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #13 Episode #11 and 13"
    - March of Time: Vol. 13 Issues 11 and 13, undated (Offsite-box 2805, Item 6)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 13 Episode #11 and 13"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 7)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #1 and 2". On side case label: "108. March of TIME Vol 14, E 1 and 2"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 8)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #1 and 2". On side case label: "125. March of Time Vol. 14 1 and 2"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 9)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #3 and 4". On side case label: "102. March of TIME Vol. 14, E. 3 and 4"
    - March of Time: Vol 14 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 10)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #3 and 4"
    - March of Time: Vol 14 Issues 5 and 17 and Vol 15 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 11)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 #7 Vol 14 #5 Vol 14 #17"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 6, 8, and 10, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 12)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On side case label: "MOT Vol 14 6 8 10". On cassette label: "Title: March of Time -- The Cold War 1-94340 1)The Cold War: Act I -- France Volume XIV, Iss. 6 2)Crisis in Italy; Act II Volume XIV Iss. 8 3)Battle For Greece: Act III Volume XIV Iss. 10". Includes a note: "Archives"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 7-9, undated (Offsite-box 2807, Item 13)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: March of Time Volume #14 Episode #7, 8, and 9
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 7-9, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 1)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #14 Episode #7, 8, and 9"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 10-12, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 2)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #10, 11, and 12". On side case label: "106. March of TIME Vol. 14, E 10, 11, and 12"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 10-12, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 3)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #10, 11, and 12"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issue 13, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 4)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On side case label: "MOT Vol 14 13". On top cassette label: "Festival March of Times White Collar Girls Vol. XIV Issue 13 1-1". On side cassette label: "Tile: "Value"/"Cable TV"/"Nosey Neighbor"/Cinemax-"Testimonial" Length: :60 :90/:60 :90/:60 :90/:60"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 13-15, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 5)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #13, 14, and 15". On side case label: "97. March of TIME Vol. 14, E. 13, 14, 15"
    - March of Time: Vol 14 Issues 13-15, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 6)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #13, 14, and 15"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 16 and 18 and Vol. 15 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 7)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #16 and 18 Vol 15 Episode #1". On side case label: "105. March of TIME Vol. 14, E16 and 18 Vol. 15, E1"
    - March of Time: Vol. 14 Issues 16 and 18 and Vol. 15 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 8)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 14 Episode #16 and 18 Vol 15 Episode 1"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issues 4-5 and 8, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 9)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 Episode #4, 5 and 8". On side case label: "99. March of TIME Vol. 15, E. 4,5,8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issues 4-5 and 8, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 10)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 Episode #4, 5 and 8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issues 9-11, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 11)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol. 15 9,10,11"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issues 9-11, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 12)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 #9 Vol 15 #10 Vol 15 #11"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issue 12 and Vol. 16 Issue 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 13)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 Episode #12 Vol 16 Episode #1 and 2"
    - March of Time: Vol. 15 Issue 12 and Vol. 16 Issue 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 14)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 15 Episode #12 Vol 16 Episode #1 and 2"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 3-5, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 15)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 16 Episode #3, 4 and 5". On side case label: "104. March of TIME Vol. 16, E 3, 4,5"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 3-5, undated (Offsite-box 2808, Item 16)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 16 Episode #3, 4 and 5"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 6-8, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 1)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #16 Episode #6, 7, and 8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 6-8, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 2)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 16 EP 6/7/8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 6-8, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 3)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 16 EP 6/7/8". On side case label: "115. March of TIME 6/7/8 Vol 16 NOS 6,7,8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 16 Issues 6-8, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 4)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #16 Episode #6, 7, and 8"
    - March of Time: Vol. 17 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 5)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 17 EP 1"
    - March of Time: Vol. 17 Issues 1-3, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 6)
      1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On front case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 17 Episode #1, 2 and 3". On side case label: "96. March of TIME Vol. 17, Ep 1,2 and 3"
    - March of Time: Vol. 17 Issues 1-3, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 7)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 17 Episode #1, 2 and 3"
    - March of Time: Vol. 17 Issues 4-6, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 8)
      1 videocassettes (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #17 Episode #4, 5, and 6". Includes a note: "Vol. XVII issue #6 Formosa - Island of Promise August 1951"
    - March of Time: Vol. 17 Issues 4-6, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 9)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #17 Episode #4, 5, and 6"
    - March of Time: Specials: Ramparts We Watch: Part 1, 1979 August 20 (Offsite-box 2809, Item 10)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "Ramparts We Watch Part 1 Time-Life 8/20/79"
    - March of Time: Specials: Ramparts We Watch: Part 2, 1979 August 20 (Offsite-box 2809, Item 11)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "Ramparts We Watch Part 2 Time-Life 8/20/79"
    - March of Time: Specials: We are the Marines, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 12)
      1 videocassette (U-matic) (56 min., 43 sec.): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time "We are the Marines" 56:53 Pt. I"
    - March of Time: Specials: We are the Marines, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 13)
      1 videocassettes (U-matic) (9 min., 36 sec.): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time "We Are The Marines" 9:36 Pt. II"
    - March of Time: Untitled, undated (Offsite-box 2809, Item 14)
      1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On side cassette label: "78. March of TIME [no date]"
    - Time Warner: The Changing Face of Media and Entertainment, 1995 May 18 (Offsite-box 2809, Item 15)
      1 videocassette (VHA) (10 min., 50 sec.): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "Time Warner: The Changing Face of Media and Entertainment 5/18/95 10:50"
  - Subseries IV.B. Commercially Distributed, 1987-1988, undated; 1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
    The Commercially Distributed subseries contains videocassettes that were produced for the general public to purchase.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - March of Time: America at War: Friend and Foe Part 3, 1987 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 1)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (113 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents America at War Friend and Foe Part 3". Includes a note: "Vol. XI issue #4 Inside China Today December 1944"
    - March of Time: America at War: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 2)
      One box set. Originally included six vhs tapes but one tape is missing. Cassettes included in the box set:
      1 videocassette (VHS) (116 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time presents America at War Friend and Foe Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (87 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents America at War Friend and Foe Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (114 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents America at War On the Homefront"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (122 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents America at War American Defense Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (116 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents America at War American Defense Part 2"
    - March of Time: American Lifestyles 1939-1950: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 3)
      One box set which includes six vhs tapes:
      1 videocassette (VHS) (73 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 Show Business: The War Years 1939-1945"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (92 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 Show Business: The Postwar Years 1946-1950"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (89 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 The American Family: The War Years 1941-1945"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (89 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 The American Family: The Postwar Years 1946-1948"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (90 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 America's Youth 1940-1950"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (105 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents American Lifestyles 1939-1950 American Fashion and Leisure 1945-1950"
    - March of Time: The Cold War 1946-1951: Changing Attitudes 1946-1948, 1989 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 4)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (88 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Cold War 1946-1951 Changung Attitudes 1946-1948"
    - March of Time: The Cold War 1946-1951: Peace or War? 1949-1950, 1989 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 5)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (83 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Cold War 1946-1951 Peace or War? 1949-1950"
    - March of Time: The Cold War 1946-1951: Time Marches On 1950-1951, 1989 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 6)
      1 videocassette (vhs) (105 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Cold War 1946-1951 Time Marches On 1950-1951"
    - March of Time: The Great Depression: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 7)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (88 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression Time Marches in 1935 Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (88 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression Economy Blues 1935-1936 Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (82 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression Trouble Beyon Our Shores 1935-1936 Part 3"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (111 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression War and Labor Woes 1936 Part 4"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (106 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression Prosperity Ahead 1936 Part 5"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (97 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents The Great Depression Reality and America's Dreams 1937 Part 6"
    - March of Time: Postwar Problems and Solutions: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 2810, Item 8)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (125 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Post-War Problems and Solutions America's Post-War Problems Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (119 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Post-War Problems and Solutions America's Post-War Problems Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (107 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Post-War Problems and Solutions Post-War Problems Beyond Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (125 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Post-War Problems and Solutions Post-War Problems Beyond Part 2)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (120 min): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Post-War Problems and Solutions Modern Main Stree, U.S.A."
    - March of Time: Trouble Abroad: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 2811, Item 1)
      One box set. Originally included six vhs tapes but one tape is missing. Included in the set:
      1 videocassette (VHS) (76 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trouble Abroad 1937-1939 Tension Increase 1937 Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (93 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trouble Abroad 1937-1939 Germany and Other Problems 1938 Prt 3"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (91 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trouble Abroad 1937-1939 Spotlight on War 1938 Part 4"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (75 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trouble Abroad 1937-1939 Uncle Sam: The Observer 1938-1939 Part 5"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (91 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trouble Abroad 1937-1939 War, Peace and America 1939 Part 6"
    - March of Time: Trouble Abroad: War Abroad: Depression at Home, 1988 (Offsite-box 2811, Item 2)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (71 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents Trounle Abroad 1937-1939 War Abroad: Depression at Home 1937 Part 1". Includes a note: "Vol. IV Issue #1 War In China Sept. 1937"
    - March of Time: War Breaks Out: Special Collector's Edition Box Set, 1987 (Offsite-box 2811, Item 3)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (118 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents War Breaks Out Americans Prepare Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (113 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents War Breaks Out Americans Prepare Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (107 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents War Breaks Out The Battle Beyond Part 1"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (117 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents War Breaks Out The Battle Beyond Part 2"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (124 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presnts War Breaks Out The Military Prepares"
      1 videocassette (VHS) (71 min.): 1/2 in. Title: "The March of Time Presents War Breaks Out Praying for Peace"
    - WPA Film Library Sample Reel, undated (Offsite-box 2811, Item 4)